# Mohit Saini

msaini0r@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/msaini0r/
github.com/msaini0r

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

#### Developer

Well-qualified Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 2 years of related experience.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Freelancer Jalandhar, Punjab

Freelancer Aug 2021 – Oct 2021

- · Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, CSS, JavaScript coding.
- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- Created custom mobile applications using hybrid technologies.

Campus Ambassador Jalandhar, Punjab

**Lovely Professional University** 

Jan 2021 – June 2021

- Promoted campus awareness about engagement opportunities with on-campus table tents, email and social media promotion.
- Supported campus events to increase student engagement and promote campus-wide initiatives.
- · Organized private and public events on campus for college community.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Bankist Website**

- · Created a modern and minimalistic bank website.
- Added features like lazy image loading, Slider with the help of JavaScript.

## **Ecommerce Website**

- · Designed the UI Part with Figma.
- Programmed this project with Html, CSS, & Bootstrap.

#### **Personal Portfolio**

- Added the CV information on the website.
- Upgraded the Portfolio with responsive blog and contact page.

#### **VPN** Website

- Streamlined this website with testimonial and pricing section.
- Gained Knowledge about hover effect, static and relative positioning.

# **EDUCATION**

**Lovely Professional University** 

Aug 2020 - June 2024

**B.S. Computer Science** 

**Innocent Hearts School** 

Feb 2018 – June 2020

H.S. Non-Medical

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- The Complete 2022 Web Development Bootcamp
- Make Your Own App
- Yoga At Home Flexibility, Fitness, Strength & Weight Loss

## **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Java, React (Most to Least Proficient)

Interests: Music, Volleyball, Photography, Reading, Travel